<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Pranjal Das</title>
    <link>https://daspraanjal.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Pranjal Das</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright 2024, Pranjal Das</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 16:48:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://daspraanjal.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Partitions in Linux</title>
      <link>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-create-partitions-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 16:48:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-create-partitions-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>Creating and modifying disk partitions is helpful for maintaining multiple file systems on same physical drive. It can simplify the backup process and system upgradation. In this blog we will use a command line utility called fdisk to create a partition in a disk.&#xA;Partitioning Disk Using fdisk command To partition a particular disk we will perform the following steps&#xA;Locating the disk on which we will create a partition Entering into an interative fdisk tui by selecting the drive Making necessary operations on the drive Writing the operations on the drive Step 1: Locating the drive We can list all the installed storage disks in our Linux machine using the command</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Matlab in Linux</title>
      <link>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-install-matlab-in-linux/how-to-install-matlab-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 15:01:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-install-matlab-in-linux/how-to-install-matlab-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>In this blog I will show you, how to install matlab in Linux.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Format an USB Drive From Terminal</title>
      <link>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-format-an-usb-drive-from-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 14:07:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://daspraanjal.github.io/post/how-to-format-an-usb-drive-from-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Formatting an USB-stick is a pretty easy task to do, it can be done in multiple ways, like using File managers, GUI disk utility applications like Disks, GParted etc. It can also be done fairly easily from terminal and this blog will show you how to.&#xA;Which File System You Are Going To Use The file systems you can use for formatting a USB drive differ by maximum file size and operating system compatibility.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
